Riley Reid

66 Denny Cr Regina, SK Canada S4N 5J9

306 596 1010 rreid112@gmail.com rjreid.ca

SUMMARY

A driven developer that keeps up with the current coding standards offering over 10+ years of software development experience as well as 5+ years of Android development experience working on multiple apps.

You can view my portfolio at https://rjreid.ca.

EXPERIENCE

Senior Software Engineer, Lumeca

Regina, SK April 2020 - Current

Work on the Android app and the web app, which uses a Vue.js frontend with a Laravel PHP backend. Also work on a C#.NET system as well as a KTOR backend system. Responsible for developing new features in the apps, fixing any reported bugs and pushing new releases every two weeks.

Accomplishments

- Helped run the virtual clinic during the Covid-19 pandemic which allowed patients to see a doctor within minutes over a secure video call.
- Helped build and release a new product, Lumeca Connect Pro, which gives clinics a platform to see patients virtually.

Senior Android Developer, Trov

Regina, SK June 2019 - April 2020

Worked with a small mobile team on a telematics app. Handled everything from app architecture to feature development and code refactors. Had the chance to work in the iOS project a bit as well.

Accomplishments

- Lead the analytics efforts on Android. This included attending meetings with the product team to discuss events that we would like to track
- Helped the ios team with the ios app where I could to help them catch
 up as they were behind when I joined the company
- Started committing code on my first day at the company

Senior Android Developer, GasBuddy

Regina, SK Jan 2015 - June 2019

Worked on all parts of the GasBuddy app with a small Android team that consisted of 6 members. Was responsible for writing clear and concise code, pushing weekly releases to the play store, auditing pull requests, writing unit tests, fixing bugs, watching and responding to crash reports, and attending daily meetings.

Accomplishments

- Redesigned the GasBuddy app with a complete overhaul (UI and architecture) top to bottom
- Lead the teams efforts to move towards Kotlin
- Push new Beta and Production release on a weekly basis
- Always up to date on crash reports and analytics to deliver the best user experience possible
- Promoted to Team Lead which required me to lead a team of 4 Android developers.

EDUCATION

University of Regina

Bachelor of Science, Computer Science 2010 - 2015

Participated in the co-op program and completed four work terms that lasted four months each

SKILLS

- Kotlin, Java
- Android SDK
- JSON, XML
- Retrofit, RxJava 2, Dagger 2, and many more!
- Javascript, Vue.js, html, css, tailwind, PHP
- Work well as an individual as well as in a team
- Self motivator with a strong work ethic
- Keep myself organized and on task
- Working knowledge of Agile methodology

REFERENCES

Available upon request.